Guide to the David Gascoyne Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Gascoyne collection
1978-1989
GEN MSS 529
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.24
(24 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, writings (including notes, journals and manuscripts), artwork, photographs and audio cassettes which document the career of poet and translator David Gascoyne.
Gascoyne, David, 1916-2001
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are microfilmed, as noted on individual folders.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is noted on the folders or in series descriptions. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 24: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
David Emery Gascoyne, 1916-2001
The poet and translator David Emery Gascoyne was born October 10, 1916 in Harrow, England and died November 25, 2001. His early career was characterized by a precocious energy that produced two volumes of poetry ( Roman Balcony and Other Poems, 1932 and Man's Life is This Meat, 1936), a novel ( Opening Day, 1933) and a critical survey ( A Short Survey of Surrealism, 1935) by the time he was twenty. He became one of the leading representatives of British Surrealism and was an important liaison between French and British circles. His diaries from the late 1930s are particularly well known and provide an excellent picture of the Parisian avant-garde on the brink of the Second World War.
Gascoyne published several volumes of poetry in his early productive stage, but after 1956 he published little new poetry. His later work focused on lectures and appearances, essays, reviews, translations and the publication of his journals. His most criticially acclaimed later works include Night Thoughts and The Sun at Midnight. He also had a long-standing relationship with Enitharmon Press, founded in 1967 by Alan Clodd, which resulted in numerous publications.
Gascoyne's intense poetic sensitivity (often characterized as visionary or mystical) was tempered by severe depression and he devoted many years to recovery. It was during a stay at a hospital on the Isle of Wight that he met Judy Tyler Lewis, whom he married in 1975. He had four stepchildren.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Correspondence, Writings, Other Papers, and Alan Clodd Collection of David Gascoyne. The first three series are of mixed provenance, as indicated by accession numbers on individual folders.
Scope and Contents
The David Gascoyne collection encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and groups of manuscripts pertaining to David Gascoyne acquired by gift or purchase from various sources by the Beinecke Library.
The papers span most of Gascoyne's career from 1945 onward. The material from the 1940s is primarily correspondence, notebooks and journals, while later material from the 1970s through the1990s includes sound recordings, original artwork, typescripts and other material related to publication as well as notebooks.
Gascoyne's notebooks contain diverse genres of writings including notes and drafts for correspondence, prose, poetic writing, and lists (which are often bibliographic). In addition to traditional literary genres, Gascoyne's works include collections of found images and writings. One such collection, "A Little Book of Bits and Pieces," is bound into a volume; a second comprises a planned work entitled "Works of Novalis, Translated by Various Hands."
The bulk of the correspondence in the collection relates to the editing and publishing of Gascoyne's works and to the management of his literary career, though some addresses literary and philosophical topics. Other correspondence is personal, such as Gascoyne's postcards to his parents.
The largest single accession in the collection is that of Alan Clodd, Gascoyne's agent and publisher. In addition to correspondence, notebooks, artwork, photographs and audio recordings, the Alan Clodd collection includes papers from several volumes that Clodd helped prepare for publication, including Selected Prose, Selected Verse Translations and Gascoyne's planned publication Surrealism Resurveyed.
Poets, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; Surrealism; Audiocassettes; Paintings (visual works); Photographs; Sound recordings; Clodd, Alan; Gascoyne, David, 1916-2001
- Correspondence, 1945-89; Series I; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence covers topics which range from personal to literary to purely professional. All letters are incoming unless otherwise noted and all outgoing letters are holographs. Correspondence is also filed elsewhere in the collection (see the notebooks in Writings for drafts of correspondence and Correspondence for correspondence donated by Alan Clodd).
  - Barker, Sebastian, incoming and outgoing, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cailleux, Roland, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - De Zoete, Beryl, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fleischmann, Marcel, 1951 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - G_____, Tom, 1945 Nov 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Glock, Clement, outgoing, 1946 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Legge, Sheila
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Lodwick, Sheila, incoming and outgoing
  - Lockwood Memorial Library, University of Buffalo, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lodwick, Sheila, incoming and outgoing, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Murphy, Gwendolen, 1945 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poetry London, 1945 Jun (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reverchou-Jouve, Blanche, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Seligman, Marcel, "Tripartite Telegram," outgoing, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Shaw, Betty, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Tiege, Karel, Ludvík Toman, Jindřich Heisler and Toyen, 1945 Sep 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Waller, John, 1945 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified, signed "Ein Grashüpfer", 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Empty envelopes, addressed by David Gascoyne, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Writings, 1941-87; Series II; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  The series consists of two subseries: Notebooks and General Writings. Notebooks are arranged chronologically. General Writings are arranged by title of work. Some works (e.g. "The Sun at Midnight") appear in both subseries.
  Additional notebooks and writings can be found in Series IV.
  The notebooks contain poetry in a wide variety of styles (e.g. automatic writing and translated verse), drafts of correspondence, essays and reviews, and collections of found images. All notebooks are holographs.
  Where applicable, notebook descriptions have been transcribed from the cover or first page of the notebook. These descriptions often reflect the predominant contents or theme of a notebook, but rarely reflect the complete contents. Folder notes identify titles of works only when they are readily apparent.
  General Writings consist of holograph and typescript drafts related to the preparation of Gascoyne's work for potential publication. Of particular interest is a collection of found images, "Works of Novalis."
  - Notebooks
    - "Themes: Titles, etc.", 1941-44 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "A notebook of hermetic philosophy", 1944-46 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Notes on literary topics, loose sheets, holograph, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Notebook, mostly lists, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Includes: "Notes towards a long Philosophical Poem"
    - "Notes, etc. for 'The Theocratic Revolution'," loose sheets, holograph, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
    - "The Sun at Midnight/ Miscellaneous Notes", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "The Sun at Midnight, Conclusion of Part 1", [circa 1940s]
    - "Poetry & Transcendence", [1947] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Notebook with one loose sheet, holograph, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Includes: Draft of essay on Léon Chestov; Jouve translations
    - "Commonplace book", 1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "Bride of Quietness/Cahier de Meditation", [circa 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "Return of the God-Conscious", [circa 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "Bibliography" (for "Return of the God-Conscious"), [circa 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "A Little Book of Bits and Pieces", [circa 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 31)
      A bound scrapbook of collected found images and printed quotations
    - "At Venice", 1950 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Reconciliatory Reconnoitre," poem, draft and notes on phenomenology, holograph, [circa 1950s] (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Notebook, [circa 1978-80] (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Includes: translations of works by Hölderlin, Eluard, and Jean-Paul de Dadelsen
    - "Notes on Translation: Essays, etc.", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Includes: introduction to Surrealism Resurveyed
    - "Reviews, Articles, etc.," 2 volumes, [1979] (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Notebook, 1979-80 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Includes: reviews of works by Sebastian Barker and Marcel Jouhandeau; notes on Surrealism Resurveyed
    - "Translations: Rough Drafts," 2 volumes, [circa 1979-80] (Box 4, Folder 38)
      Includes: translations of works by Follain, Supervielle, Soupault, and Yves de Bayser
    - Notebook and nine loose sheets, holograph, [1980] (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Includes: notes on Benjamin Fondane
    - Notebook, [1980] (Box 4, Folder 40)
      Includes: homage to Denis Roche; reviews of Man Ray: The Photographic Image and Voyons Voir
    - Notebook, [circa 1980-81] (Box 4, Folder 41)
      Includes: translations; review of Rimbaud: a Critical Introduction by C.A. Hackett; review of Sous de vastes portiques by J.J. Mayoux
    - Notebook on Louis Aragon, [circa 1980-81] (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Notebook and one typed sheet, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      Includes: review of Frederick Tsistan's Le Tribulations heroiques de Balthasar Kober; biographical summary of Gascoyne's life and work
    - Drafts of correspondence and prose, 1983-87 (Box 4, Folder 44-48)
      Includes: letters to J. D. Sprack, John Deane, and Graham Ackroyd; draft of comments on Louis Aragon
    - Drafts of correspondence and prose, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      Includes: letters to Natalie Wheen, Tony Astbury, Herbert Becket and Harold Pinter; an introduction of the work of George Barker
    - "Notes on Idealist and Realist Phenomenologies," typed sheets, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - General Writings
    - "Anton Von Webern," essay, holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "Blind Man's Buff," Part I, prose, typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - "Bride of Quietness," notes, holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - "Criticism and elucidation of the conception of freedom," prose, holograph, undated
    - Emblems and Allegories, holograph and typescript, corrected, circa 1946 (Box 5, Folder 54-60)
    - "Eyes in the Back of the Head," projected autobiography, holograph, 1987 Dec 14 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - "The Last Judgement," holograph, [1946?]
    - "Leon Chestov: After Ten Years Silence," essay, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - "Letter to an adopted Godfather," addressed to H.M., typescript, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - "The Man With the Blue Guitar," by Wallace Stevens, radio broadcast, typescript, annotated, 1955 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - "Night Thoughts," radio broadcast, typescript, corrected, 1955 Dec 6 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Opera, untitled, typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - "Piazza Piece," typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - "A Portfolio of New Poems", 1948
      Includes: "A Vagrant;" "Rex Mundi;" "September Sun"
    - "Requiem for Priaulx Rainier," holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - "The Sun at Midnight," typescript, corrected, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 69-73)
    - "Works of Novalis, Translated by Various Hands"
      - One sheet of notes, holograph, undated
      - Collected prints and found images, undated
    - Various Titles, Poems, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1936, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
      Includes: "Reconciliatory Reconnoitre;" "Birth of a Prince;" "Come Dungeon Dark;" "Hymn;" "The Moon Over London;" "A Vagrant;" "Rose Carved of Oak"
- Other Papers, 1944-54; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Material is arranged roughly by format.
  The series contains collections of found images and writings, administrative papers, clippings and writings of others. The collections of found images and writings are clearly related to Gascoyne's surrealist writing, though no association with a particular work is evident
  - Collection of found images and writing related to alchemy, religion and religious iconography, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Collection of pages from publications by Roger Vitrac, Benjamin Péret, Harry Crosby, André Breton and others, undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Contract with the British Broadcasting Corporation for the broadcast of "In defence of humanism", 1946 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Benjamin Britten portrait by Kenneth Green, print, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - British Library pass, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Clippings and ephemera, [circa 1945-46] (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - "Around and about Gertrude Stein," by Adrian Carins, typescript, 1946 Feb 23 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - "Three Early Poems," by unidentified author, one printed sheet, undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Document box annotated by David Gascoyne, undated
    Annotation reads: "PIERRE (TOUGH OBSCENITY D'ASSISSI) WATSON/ DANGER--URGENT/ ON NO CONDITION/ TO BE UNDERTAKEN/ PRIVATE: PUBLIC WASTER'S PAPERS/ OF NO WEIGHT &/ YOUR STATE OF MINE/ OF VITAL INTEREST TO"
- Alan Clodd Collection of David Gascoyne, circa 1910-2002; Series IV; 4.59; (12 boxes)
  The series contains six subseries: Correspondence, Writings (including notebooks and general writings), Other Papers, Artwork, Photographs, and Audio Recordings.
  Alan Clodd's collection contains not only papers resulting from his work as Gascoyne's publisher and agent, but also notebooks, artwork and family photographs, which were likely given to him by Gascoyne.
  The Correspondence subseries consists of Alan Clodd's correspondence and David Gascoyne's correspondence. Alan Clodd's correspondence (incoming, outgoing and third party) relates to the publication of various of Gascoyne's works, to the management of Gascoyne's literary career and to Clodd's effort to secure an official honor for Gascoyne from the British government. Clodd's correspondence also contains several folders of letters and cards from Judy Gascoyne, which cover a range of personal and professional topics.
  David Gascoyne's correspondence (incoming and outgoing) is primarily professional in nature, relating to appearances and publications. There are, however, personal letters inlcuding seven folders of postcards written by him to his parents Leslie and Winfred Gascoyne. Some correspondence related to the publication of specific works is filed in the Writings subseries, reflecting Clodd's arrangement of his papers.
  The Writings subseries includes Notebooks, General Writings and Writings of Others. In addition to notes, drafts and typescripts, correspondence related to the publication of a particular work is filed here. Writings of Others include a typescript of Judy Gascoyne's memoir and material from several publications of Jeremy Reed.
  Other Papers include clippings and reviews related to David Gascoyne.
  The Artwork subseries consists mainly of gouache works on paper, all by David Gascoyne. Some are signed, titled or dated.
  The Photographs subseries contains a few professional portraits of David Gascoyne, snapshots of Gascoyne and others and nineteen folders of Gascoyne family photographs. Subjects of the family photographs include David Gascoyne as a child and an adult, Gascoyne's parents, Gascoyne's younger twin brothers John and Tony (and their families) and Judy Gascoyne. Some of these photographs are identified with names, dates (ranging from the 1910s to the 1990s) or descriptions.
  The Audio Recordings subseries consists of six audio cassettes containing recordings of David Gascoyne interviews, readings and performances.
  - Correspondence
    This subseries consists of Alan Clodd's correspondence and David Gacoyne's correspondence. Within each group, letters are arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Letters with only a first name identified and letters from unidentified correspondents or with illegible signatures are filed at the end of each group. Two folders of letters relating to the nomination of David Gascoyne for a public honor are filed at the end of Alan Clodd's correspondence.
    Most of these approximately forty letters are addresed to the office of Prime Minister Tony Blair and express support of an official public honor for David Gascoyne. Authors include Sebastian Barker, Jeremy Reed and Roger Scott. These letters are accompanied by copies of letters from Alan Clodd to the letter writers.
    - Alan Clodd Correspondence
      - Adam International Review, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 83)
      - Andre Deutsch Ltd., 1974 (Box 8, Folder 84)
      - Atlas Press, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 85)
      - Barker, George, [1976] May 28 (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - Barker, Jack, 1993 Sep (Box 8, Folder 87)
      - Benford, Colin T., 1981 Jul 15 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - Bonython Bookshop, 1997 Oct 8 (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - Braybrooke, Neville, 1975-78 (Box 8, Folder 90)
      - The British Library, Department of Manuscripts, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 91)
      - Brode, Anthony, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 92)
      - Callow, Simon, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 93)
        Copy of letter to David and Judy Gascoyne acompanied by introduction to Night Thoughts
      - Carcanet Press Limited, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      - Court of Protection, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 95)
      - Crummles Theatre Company, 1986 Jul 23 (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - David Hingham Associates, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 97)
      - Durrell, Lawrence, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 98)
      - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1975-77 (Box 8, Folder 99)
      - Fancutt, Rev. Walter, 1978 Oct (Box 8, Folder 100)
      - Frank Cass & Co. Ltd., 1973-78 (Box 8, Folder 101)
      - [Garetzner?], Anne, 1977 Jun 14 (Box 8, Folder 102)
      - Gascoyne, Judy (and David), 1987-2002 (Box 8, Folder 103-108)
      - Godley, Adam, undated (Box 8, Folder 109)
      - Green, Martin, 1997 Oct 4 (Box 8, Folder 110)
      - H_____, Beatrice, [1978?] Sep 28 (Box 8, Folder 111)
      - Hamish Hamilton Ltd., 1977 Aug 2 (Box 8, Folder 112)
      - Hammond, Paul, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 113)
      - Hesketh, Phoebe, 1983 Feb 5 (Box 8, Folder 114)
      - Isle of Wight. County Council, 1978 Jul 25 (Box 9, Folder 115)
      - Isle of Wight. Inspector of Taxes, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 116)
      - [Kabraji], Fredoon, 1978 Oct 30 (Box 9, Folder 117)
      - LaHurd, Ryan, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 118)
      - Lewis, Judy
        See: Gascoyne, Judy (and David)
      - Lösche, Heidrun, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 119)
      - London Magazine, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 120)
      - Lowell, Robert, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 121)
      - Lucescu-Boutcher, Arta, 1995 Oct 17 (Box 9, Folder 122)
        Accompanied by a copy of her interview with Gascoyne on Benjamin Fondane
      - Marnau, Fred, 1974 Dec 4 (Box 9, Folder 123)
      - Marnau, P., 1996 Oct 25 (Box 9, Folder 124)
      - McFarlin Library, University of Tulsa, 1977-79 (Box 9, Folder 125)
      - Munton, Alan, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 126)
      - New Society, 1978 Oct (Box 9, Folder 127)
      - O'Connor, Philip, 1978 Sep 28 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      - Official Solicitor to the Supreme Court, 1974-77 (Box 9, Folder 129)
      - Orend, Karl, 1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 130)
      - Oxford University Press, 1976-79 (Box 9, Folder 131)
      - Potts, Anne Frances, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 132)
      - Pratt, Annie, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 133)
      - Quinn, Sister Bernetta, 1973-76 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      - Remy, Michel, 1968-76 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Scott, Roger, 1996-99 (Box 9, Folder 136-137)
      - Shaw-Lawrence, Bettina, 1978 Sep (Box 9, Folder 138)
      - Sidgwick & Jackson Ltd., 1975 (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Skoob Books Publishing Ltd., 1992 (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - Smith, Chris, 1999 Mar 30 (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - Stanford, Derek, 1975 Feb (Box 9, Folder 142)
      - Stevenson, Quentin, 1973 Sep 20 (Box 9, Folder 143)
      - Stuart-Smith, Stephen, 1995-2001 (Box 9, Folder 144)
      - [Trevelyan], Julian, 1975-76 (Box 9, Folder 145)
      - Trevelyan, Raleigh, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 146)
      - Tuohy, Frank, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 147)
      - Weidenfeld & Nicolson, 1985 Jan (Box 9, Folder 148)
      - [White?], Eric, 1978 Sep 26 (Box 9, Folder 149)
      - Writers' Action Group, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - _____, Anne, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 151)
      - _____, Leonora, 1978 Sep 12 (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - _____, Tony, circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 153)
      - Letters related to the nomination of David Gascoyne for a public honor, 1997-2000 (Box 9, Folder 154-155)
    - David Gascoyne Correspondence
      - Incoming
        - Abercrombie, Ralph, undated (Box 10, Folder 156)
        - Adam International Review, 1969 Nov 21 (Box 10, Folder 157)
        - Andre Deutsch Limited, 1956 Aug 9 (Box 10, Folder 158)
        - B____, [Barby?], 1979 Feb (Box 10, Folder 159)
        - Barker, George, undated (Box 10, Folder 160)
        - Benford, Colin T., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 161)
        - Bernard, Oliver, 1978 Nov 29 (Box 10, Folder 162)
        - Beylié, Laurence de, undated (Box 10, Folder 163)
        - Bielesz, Peter, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 164)
        - Boylan, Francis and William Hall, 1970 Apr 18 (Box 10, Folder 165)
        - Bridson, Vivien, 1981 Feb 10 (Box 10, Folder 166)
        - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1955-56 (Box 10, Folder 167)
        - [Buckroy?], Jon and Carol, after 1971 (Box 10, Folder 168)
        - Caetani, Marguerite, undated (Box 10, Folder 169)
        - Calvert, Robert, undated (Box 10, Folder 170)
        - Cambridge Poetry Festival 1975, 1975 Feb 3 (Box 10, Folder 171)
        - Canadian Catholic Review, 1997 Mar 6 (Box 10, Folder 172)
        - Carpenter, Maurice, 1969 Oct 21 (Box 10, Folder 173)
        - Chatto and Windus Ltd., 1956 Sep 5 (Box 10, Folder 174)
        - Clare, Terry, 1970-71 (Box 10, Folder 175)
        - Codrington, Ursula, undated (Box 10, Folder 176)
        - Conran, Paul, undated (Box 10, Folder 177)
        - Court of Protection, chief clerk, 1969 Dec 19 (Box 10, Folder 178)
        - [Fenis?], Paul, undated (Box 10, Folder 179)
        - Fletcher, Ian, undated (Box 10, Folder 180)
        - Frank Cass & Company Ltd., 1968 Mar 18 (Box 10, Folder 181)
        - Gamble, Tony, undated (Box 10, Folder 182)
        - [Gascoyne?], Joan, 1976 Mar 24 (Box 10, Folder 183)
        - Gascoyne, Leslie, 1954 Jan (Box 10, Folder 184)
        - Gascoyne, Winfred, 1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 185)
        - Gibson, James, 1970 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 186)
        - Gittins, [R.?], 1969 Nov 16 (Box 10, Folder 187)
        - Guevara, Merand, undated (Box 10, Folder 188)
        - Hope, Warren, 1973 May 10 (Box 10, Folder 189)
        - Hoy, Peter, 1979 Mar 11 (Box 10, Folder 190)
        - Jackaman, Rob, undated (Box 10, Folder 191)
        - [Johnson], Buffie, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 192)
        - Lambert, Charles, 1973 Apr (Box 10, Folder 193)
        - Lehman, John, 1964 Jul 3 (Box 10, Folder 194)
        - Linden, Eddie S., 1978 Apr 23 (Box 10, Folder 195)
        - MacDonald & Co. Ltd., 1956 May 8 (Box 10, Folder 196)
        - Manning, Hugo, 1970 May 16 (Box 10, Folder 197)
        - Mechanical-Copyright Protection Society Limited, 1956 Sep 26 (Box 10, Folder 198)
        - Moray, Barbara, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 199)
        - New Society Publishers, 1982 Feb 7 (Box 10, Folder 200)